taca.com 2015-03-22

# Privacy Policy to protect your personal data | Avianca

## General privacy policy

### 1\. Who we are

The Airlines Aerovías del Continente Americano S.A., **Avianca** ; **Tampa Cargo S.A**.; commercial companies established in the Republic of Colombia, **Aerolíneas Galápagos S.A.** , **Aerogal** ; a commercial company incorporated in the Republic of Ecuador, and the airlines in the Grupo Taca: **Taca International Airlines** **S.A.** , incorporated in the Republic of El Salvador; **Líneas Aéreas Costarricenses S.A., Lacsa,, incorporated in the Republic of Costa Rica; Trans American Airlines S.A.** , incorporated in the Republic of Peru; Aviateca S.A., incorporated under the laws of Guatemala; hereon referred to both individually as well as collectively as THE AIRLINES, including under this the products and services rendered by other companies subordinated to any of the above who, for all purposes of the provision and marketing of air passenger transport services, and related services and products such as tourism packages, air and/or ground transport services, express courier services, airport services, training services, loyalty programs, may act under the commercial brands AVIANCA, AEROGAL, AVIATECA, LACSA, TACA, TACA PERU, TACA REGIONAL, TACA CARGO, TAMPA CARGO, AVIANCA CARGO, AVIANCA SERVICES, AVIANCA TOURS, AVIANCA EXPRESS, FLYBOX, DEPRISA, LIFEMILES, PREFERENCIA "Programa para viajes empresariales", or just under the commercial brand AVIANCA, all respectively responsible and/or tasked with the treatment of personal information.

Avianca Holdings S.A., (previously Avianca Taca Holding S.A.) is a Panamanian company, established as an investment firm, serving as an instrument for the execution of the shareholders agreement that gave way to the integration process of THE AIRLINES.

### 2\. Purpose of the Terms and Conditions of the Treatment of Information and Personal Information of THE AIRLINES

This document contains our policy regarding the treatment of personal information and data, and it discloses what information we collect during the provision of our services, and to what end, how we use it, when we share it and how we protect it, as well as the rights of the holders of such information, and the procedures to enforce them.   

We, THE AIRLINES, recognize the importance of the security, privacy and confidentiality of the personal information that our travelers, clients and users provide us through the different channels used to market our products and services (such as Web sites, retail offices, call centers), and we are committed to their protection and proper handling, in accordance with the legal regime for the protection of personal information and data that is applicable in each territory that we operate in.   

This document is applicable to the treatment of the information received from our travelers, clients and users in each of our business units:  Deprisa, Avianca Tours, LifeMiles, PREFERENCIA "Programa para viajes empresariales", Avianca Services, Avianca Cargo and Avianca Express, and constitutes the legal reference framework for the specific policies available at:

www.avianca.com, [www.taca.com](http://www.taca.com/index.aspx?mnu=&rcod=LMqY01kynlbLKtg6GIgrzg%3d%3d&pa=EC&es=0&), [www.deprisa.com](http://www.deprisa.com/), [www.lifemiles.com](https://www.lifemiles.com/index.aspx), [www.preferenciacorporativo.com](https://www.preferenciacorporativo.com/PreferenciaCorporativo/HomePrincipal.aspx?ReturnUrl=%2fPreferenciaCorporativo%2fHomeAutenticado.aspx&lan=EN), [www.aviancaservices.com](http://www.aviancaservices.com/), [www.aviancacargo.com](http://www.aviancacargo.com/index.aspx), [www.aerogal.com.ec](http://www.aerogal.com.ec/?lang=en), [www.tacaregional.com](http://www.tacaregional.com/), [www.flybox.co](http://www.flybox.co/como_se_usa.aspx), [www.aviancaexpress.com](http://temp.aviancaexpress.com/content/page.aspx?ID=93), [link.avianca.com](http://link.avianca.com/PortalAgencias/HomePublico.aspx), [www.sociosyamigos.com](http://www.sociosyamigos.com/). Each of these Web sites has posted the terms and conditions applicable to the products and services listed therein, which may be consulted and reviewed at any time for further information.

The Web sites listed hereunder may be deactivated or their domain may be changed, in accordance with the reorganization processes we may implement from time to time, said changes will be informed to our travelers, clients and users on a timely fashion.

### 3\. Personal information and data that we obtain

THE AIRLINES collect personal information and data from our travelers, clients and users, which may include, completely or in part, in accordance with the needs of each product and/or service, among others, the following:

| ​Names and last names | Date of birth and gender | Postal and electronic addresses (personal and/or work) | Card holder information (names and last names, identification type and number) | ​Profession or occupation  
---|---|---|---|---  
​Identification type and number | ​Civil status and/or relationship with minors, or individuals with a handicap who are requesting our services | ​Fax (personal and/or work) | ​Information of the address where the card holder receives his/her financial statements | ​Company they work in and position  
​Nationality and country of residence | ​Fixed and cellular phone numbers (personal and/or work) | ​Credit card information (number, bank, expiration date) | Client IP, through cookies  | ​Frequent Flier card number and information about transactions and activities related to the LifeMiles frequent flier program  

Any information necessary to facilitate the trip or other services, including the name(s) of any accompanying individual(s), contacts in case of an accident or contingency, seat preference, special foods or medical requirements.

Purchase channel information (such as travel agencies, direct sales points or representatives or agents, call center, Web sites). 

Use of products and services such as self-check-in machines, notification of the status of flights, and on-line check-in.

Personal information and data collected through surveys, focus groups or other means of market research. 

Information required by the representatives of the sales and/or customer relations areas, in order to tend to requests, claims or complaints.

Biometrical data. 

This information and data may be stored and/or processed on servers located in computer centers, be it our own or contracted from third parties, located in several countries, which has been authorized by our travelers, clients and users, when agreeing to this Privacy Policy.

Furthermore, and for security reasons, we THE AIRLINES may collect, store, share and compare with the different administrative and control, and national or international oversight authorities, police authorities or judicial authorities, the biometric information about our travelers, clients and users, that have been obtained through image, audio or video recording devices located in our facilities, such as administrative offices, points of sale, VIP lounges, airport service modules, call centers, among others.  We THE AIRLINES will report this fact to the general public through the publication of Privacy Notices located at the places where said data are collected.  

#### Term of the treatment of the personal information and data   

The information provided by the travelers, clients and users shall be stored for a period of up to ten (10) years, counted as of the date of the latest treatment, in order to allow us to comply with the legal and/or contractual obligations borne by us, especially from an accounting, fiscal and tax perspective.   

#### Accuracy of information   

Travelers, clients and users shall provide us with accurate and true information about their personal data and information to formalize the reservation, and in order to make it possible to provide the contracted services, as well as any other services they required, and under which conditions they agree to provide the information required. 

We THE AIRLINES assume the information provided will be true and accurate and will not verify it, nor will we assume the obligation to verify the identity of the traveler, client or user, or the accuracy, currency, sufficiency or authenticity of the data provided by each or any of them.  We, therefore, shall assume no responsibility for damages of any nature, that may be the result of the lack of accuracy, currency, sufficiency or authenticity of the information, including damages and consequential damages that may be the result of a namesake situation or identity theft.

#### Information about children and underage teenagers  

Children and underage teenagers may be users of the products and services we offer, as long as they act through, or under proper authorization from, their parents or those who are responsible for them.

We THE AIRLINES shall oversee the proper use of the personal information of children and underage teenagers, ensuring that the treatment of their data will respect their greater interest and their fundamental rights and, in as much as possible, taking their opinion into account, as holders of their personal information.

### 4\. Purpose of the treatment of personal information

The information collected is used to process, confirm, comply with, and provide the services and/or products acquired, either directly or indirectly, with the intervention of other airlines or third-party vendors of products or services, as well as to promote and advertise our activities, products and services, transact, make reports to the different national and international administrative, control and oversight authorities, police or judicial authorities, banking institutions and/or insurance companies, for internal administrative and/or commercial purposes such as market research, audits, accounting reports, statistical analysis, billing and the offering and/or acknowledgment of the benefits inherent to our loyalty programs.   

We THE AIRLINES, on account of our activity, are obligated to provide a series of information about the passengers or cargo or courier packages transported, to the aeronautical, customs and immigration authorities, in addition to regulatory government bodies or national and international security institutions, prior to the departure of flights or after landing in each territory of destination, or at any time after the transport contract has been fulfilled.  As a general rule, the information refers to the identity information of the passengers on board, as well as the information included in their corresponding travel documentation (such as passport, visa, etc.) or related to the goods transported.   

By agreeing to this General Privacy Policy, our travelers, clients and users, as holders of the collected data, authorize THE AIRLINES to treat such data and information, be it in part or in full, including the collection, storage, recording, use, circulation, processing, suppression, broadcast and/or transfer to third countries of the data provided, for the performance of the activities related to the services and products acquired, such as the making of the reservation, modifications, cancellations and itinerary changes, reimbursements, servicing of claims, queries and complaints, payment of compensations and indemnifications, accounting records, mail, processing and verification of credit and debit cards, along with other payment instruments, identification of fraud and prevention of asset laundering and any other illegal or criminal activities, and/or for the operation of loyalty programs and other purposes defined hereunder.   

We hereby notify that third-party vendors may be involved in these activities (such as vendors providing flight reservation and booking services, security tools for the processing of bank transactions, call centers and tourism services operators), banking institutions, insurance companies, our representatives or agents, and that said activities may be performed in countries other than those where the service is contracted or the product is purchased, notwithstanding other purposes that may have been informed hereunder and of the terms and conditions of each of the products and services inherent to each of our business units.

Furthermore, our travelers, clients and users, as holders of the collected data, by agreeing to this privacy policy are authorizing us to:   

Use the data provided by them electronically, through Web sites, smart-phone applications, or electronic kiosks, among others, to send them the boarding pass or the document confirming the transaction, to their registered e-mails.   

Use the information provided by them, for purposes of marketing our products and services, as well as the products and services of third parties with whom THE AIRLINES have a business relationship.   

Sharing the personal information with commercial representatives, tourism operators, hotels, among others, as required for the handling of the reservations for flight or travel plans, or for services such as car-rentals or hotel room reservations.  

Provide the personal information to control and oversight authorities, be they police or judicial authorities, on account of a legal or regulatory requirement and/or use or disclose this information and the personal data in the defense of their rights and/or equity when said defense holds a relationship with the products and/or services contracted by their travelers, clients and users.  

Allow access to the personal data and information to auditors or third parties contracted to perform internal or external audit processes inherent to the commercial activities we perform.  

Consult and update the personal information or data, at any time, in order to keep such information up-to-date. 

Contract the storage and/or processing of the personal information and data, with third parties, in order to ensure the correct execution and performance of the contracts that we have signed, under the security and confidentiality standards that we are obligated to maintain.  

Transfer and broadcast the personal information and data to countries other than those where they were collected, and for such we, THE AIRLINES, will protect such information and data in accordance with the security and confidentiality standards set forth hereunder.  

Transfer the personal data to the eventual buyer of one of our business units, for which purpose we will provide timely notice to the travelers, clients and users who are holders of the personal information, in order for them to exercise their rights to update, amend or suppress the personal information as allowed to them in accordance with applicable law.   

### 5\. Use of cookies and web beacons

We THE AIRLINES may use cookies, Web beacons and any other such technologies on our web sites and on the electronic devices used to access said Web sites, in order to know the origin, activities and preferences of travelers, clients and users when browsing the Web, increasing the functionality and accessibility of the Web sites, verifying that the users are compliant with the criteria required to process their requests and to adapt their products and services to the needs of users, being able to gain access to the following overall information:

​Type of browser and operating system used | Web sites visited | ​IP address | ​Time spent browsing  
---|---|---|---  
​Device language | ​Links accessed | ​Site visited before browsing Avianca.com ​  

These cookies, Web beacons and similar technologies may be disabled and deleted by the users whenever he/she wishes. To this end, Users may consult and/or request assistance from the Internet browser they are using.   

### 6\. Protection, security and confidentiality of the information

The information about our travelers, clients and users is key for THE AIRLINES.  We have defined policies, procedures and information security standards whose purpose is to protect and preserve the integrity, confidentiality and availability of the information, independently from the media or format that it is in, its temporary or permanent location, or the way in which it is broadcast.  In this sense, we support ourselves on technological security tools and implement industry-wide security practices which include: the broadcast and storage of sensitive information using secure mechanisms, such as encryption, the use of safe protocols; assurance of technological components, restriction of access to the information only to authorized personnel, backing-up of the information, practices involving the safe development of software, among others.   

Third parties contracted by THE AIRLINES shall be equally obligated to adhere to, and abide by, the policies and security of information manuals, as well as to the security protocols that we apply to all our processes.

All contract between THE AIRLINES an third parties (contractors, external consultants, temporary collaborators, etc.) that involves treatment of the personal information and data, includes a confidentiality agreement detailing their commitments towards the protection, care, security and preservation of its confidentiality, integrity and privacy.  

### 7\. Procedure to exercise the rights of information holders

Travelers, clients and users are entitled to access the personal information and data under our control, and to exercise the rights allowed to them as holders of said information, under the terms and norms for the protection of information that are applicable to them, and in accordance with he contents of this Privacy Policy.

For purposes of personal information which is processed or treated in Colombia, the procedures to exercise such holder rights shall be that set forth under Law 1581 of 2012.

Travelers, clients and users are entitled to consulting and knowing the details of the treatment of the personal information and data we undertake, as well as to correct or rectify them should they be inaccurate, incomplete, and to cancel them when they are not being utilized in accordance with the purposes and legal or contractual terms, or according to the purposes of terms set forth hereunder.

In order to enforce their rights, travelers, clients and users may exercise their rights to know, update, rectify and suppress their personal data by sending a request to the following e-mail: contactenos@avianca.com, or through the Suggestions and Claims service at www.avianca.com, or through our Call Center, in Bogota, calling the number 4013434 or when elsewhere in Colombia, by calling the number 018000953434, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.   

The following information must be included:

​Names and last names | ​Document number | ​e-Mail | ​Reference  
---|---|---|---  
​Document type | ​Telephone Number | ​Country  
  
Should any traveler, client, user, or third party believe that a specific content used in any of our contact and marketing channels, such as Web sites, smart-phone apps and kiosks is in violation of their intellectual property rights, he/she must send a communication to the above alternatives, including the following information:   

Personal information: claimant's name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address.  

True signature, along with the personal information of the holder of the intellectual property rights that have been violated, or of the person authorized to act on behalf of the holder of the property rights that have been violated.  

Precise and full indication of the contents protected under intellectual property rights, that was violated, as well as location.   

Express and clear statement that the use of the contents listed has been made without the express consent by the holder of the intellectual property rights that were violated.  

Express and clear statement, under the claimant's responsibility, that the information provided in the notice is accurate, and that the use of the contents constitutes a violation of his/her/their intellectual property rights.

Claims originating from these facts shall be subjected in treatment and solution to all applicable legal proceedings, in accordance with their nature and scope.  

### 8\. Changes to the Privacy Policy

We THE AIRLINES reserve the right to make changes or updates to this Privacy Policy at any time, in order to tend to legislative events, internal policies or new requirements in the provision or offering of our services or products. 

These modifications shall be made available to the public through the following means: billboards visible at their establishments or customer service centers, on our Web sites, on smart-phone applications or electronic kiosks (Privacy Warning), or through communications sent to the last e-mail address provided.

### 9\. Acceptance with this Privacy Policy

Each traveler, client or user hereby agrees that his/her personal information will be treated in accordance with the terms set forth under this Privacy Policy, when providing said data and information through our customer service or retail sales channels, including Call Centers, or when acquiring or using any of our products or services, or when clicking on the "Agree" function or button, or when continuing to browse our Web sites at www.avianca.com, [www.taca.com](http://www.taca.com/index.aspx?mnu=&rcod=LMqY01kynlbLKtg6GIgrzg%3d%3d&pa=EC&es=0&), [www.deprisa.com](http://www.deprisa.com/), [www.lifemiles.com](https://www.lifemiles.com/index.aspx), [www.preferenciacorporativo.com](https://www.preferenciacorporativo.com/PreferenciaCorporativo/HomePrincipal.aspx?ReturnUrl=%2fPreferenciaCorporativo%2fHomeAutenticado.aspx), [www.aviancaservices.com](http://www.aviancaservices.com/), [www.aviancacargo.com](http://www.aviancacargo.com/index.aspx), [www.aerogal.com.ec](http://www.aerogal.com.ec/?lang=en), [www.tacaregional.com](http://www.tacaregional.com/), [www.flybox.co](http://www.flybox.co/como_se_usa.aspx), [www.aviancaexpress.com](http://temp.aviancaexpress.com/content/page.aspx?ID=93), [link.avianca.com](http://link.avianca.com/PortalAgencias/HomePublico.aspx), [www.sociosyamigos.com.](http://www.sociosyamigos.com/)  

### 10\. Effective term

This General Privacy Policy shall be in effect as of the date of its posting or publication.   

**The last revision posted is from:** 25 de Julio de 2013.

**The contact details of the Companies in Colombia are:**

Address: Avenida Eldorado No. 59 – 15, Bogotá. 

Phones: In Bogota 4013434, or from other cities in Colombia 018000953434

*If you are a supplier for any of the Companies and wish to check the privacy terms applicable to your information and personal data please read our Privacy Policy for Suppliers.   

**If you are actively employed, an ex-worker, pensioner, retiree, related third party beneficiary or candidate for office in the Companies and you wish to check the privacy terms applicable to your information and personal data please read our Privacy Policy for Collaborators.   

***If you are a shareholder of Avianca S.A. and wish to check the privacy policy applicable to your information and personal data please read our privacy notice for Shareholders.​
